<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	version="5.0" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<info>
		<title>FindMyPatient V2</title>
	</info>
	<section>
		<title>FindMyPatient V2</title>
		<para>(Online extension)</para>
		<para>Software documentation</para>
		<!-- <mediaobject> -->
		<!-- <imageobject> -->
		<!-- <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" -->
		<!-- format="png" fileref="resources/hospital.png" /> -->
		<!-- </imageobject> -->
		<!-- </mediaobject> -->
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Subject description</title>
		<section>
			<title>Goal</title>

			<para>
				This project is created as a mean to show sufficient knowledge of java
				which is acquired during the Advanced Java classes at EPITA.
				During these java classes a range of technologies and best practices
				related to java is shown, this knowledge is implemented in this
				project to show sufficient knowledge about the technology and how to
				apply them in practice.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Use case</title>
			<para>
				As a use case a hospital patient management system is created
				which includes all the technologies and best practices acquired
				during java class. This system is an extension of the developed
				application	during the previous java class.
				The hospital management system which is created should be a web
				application. The main features are analyzed in the next chapter.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Subject analysis</title>
		<section>
			<para>The minimal requirements for the system are extracted from the
				specification provided on the Advanced Java webpage. The
				requirements are applied to the use case.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Major features</title>
			<para>The following 4 categories of features and associated
				requirements are extracted:
			</para>
			<para>Main application features</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>[REQ 1] Login page for authentication</para>
					<para>o Disconnect options, takes the user to the login page</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>[REQ 2] Welcome page, as a sort of dashboard</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>[REQ 3] Creation page</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>[REQ 4] Search page</para>
					<para> o Delete option </para>
					<para> o Modify option </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Technology requirements</para>
					<para>[REQ 5] Use Hibernate or JDBC to store data models</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Process requirements</para>
					<para> [REQ 6] Use Junit to test</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> [REQ 7] Scalability </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> Additional features</para>
					<para>[REQ 8] Make it possible to dynamically add new fields to the data model</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para></para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Application Feasibility</title>
			<para>To determine the feasibility we will analyze the requirements
				and determine the risk for the realization of this requirement</para>
			<para>
				<table>
					<title>Requirement analysis</title>
					<tgroup cols='3' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
						<thead>
							<row>
								<entry>Requirement</entry>
								<entry>Analysis</entry>
								<entry>Risk</entry>
							</row>
						</thead>
						<tbody>
							<row>
								<entry>[REQ1] – [REQ4]</entry>
								<entry>The creation of webpages including the communication with servlets and backend processing is covered during class and can used in this project.</entry>
								<entry>Low risk</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>[REQ5]</entry>
								<entry>The data models are simple and Hibernate and JDBC are known technologies.</entry>
								<entry>Low risk</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>[REQ6]</entry>
								<entry>The context in this project is different from the learned content during class. Since we are working with Spring and JUnit on servlets this could provide issues while testing and can result in addition time spend.</entry>
								<entry>Medium risk</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>[REQ7]</entry>
								<entry>Scalability in the context of web development is a new area which knowledge needs to be accumulated, this can result in potential extra work </entry>
								<entry>Medium risk</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>[REQ8]</entry>
								<entry>The addition of new fields in a web application is an unknown area, since the data models are static, additional technologies or methods need to be researched. This will probably result in lots of effort.</entry>
								<entry>High risk</entry>
							</row>
						</tbody>
					</tgroup>
				</table>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Data description</title>
			<para>The project mainly manages patient data, additional there is User data which will be used for authentication. Below the two data types are displayed.</para>	
			<para>
				table PATIENT here
			</para>
			<para>
				table UERT here
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Expected results</title>
			<para>The result of this project should contain the features and extracted requirements. There should be documentation which is clear enough to get the main idea of the application and its structure.</para>
		</section>


		<section>
			<title>Algorithms study</title>
			<para>The different possibilities to realize certain functions are analyzed to result in the best applicable solution.</para>	
			<section>
				<title>[A1] Saving data</title>
				<para>To the two data models User and Patient previously a specific DAO implementation is used. This implementation could handle different data models, but cannot handle dynamic data. Since the application should be scalable [REQ 7], it is preferred to have a more dynamic solution. Hibernate can be a better solution to provide this [REQ 5].</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>[A2] Searching data</title>
				<para>The application should feature a search method. Since the data should be scalable [REQ 7] and [REQ 8], the search should be able to handle dynamic fields.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>[A3] Website Responsiveness</title>
				<para>It should be able to do operations on Patients like create, modify and delete without unnecessary page reloads. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>[A4] Packaging and Architecture</title>
				<para>The different features required should be organized in a way that is maintainable. The basic functionality from the previous java semester can be used where necessary.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>[A5] Authorization and Security</title>
				<para>To provide security an authorization mechanism should be provided. The mechanism of the previous project will be used. A method should be created to save the User credentials and status for each connected in parallel.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>[A6] Software configuration management</title>
				<para>To control the different version of the used packages a system needs to be used.</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Scope of the application</title>
				<para>The application is restricted to the features specified in chapter Major features. 
					Additional features which are out of scope:
				</para>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>The graphical design of the website (basics representation be implemented).</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Additional security: e.g. encryption of the http session, encryption of saved User data.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>



	</section>
</article>
